Hey Michelle, how are you today?
헤이 미셸, 오늘 어때요?
I'm good, Lindsay. How are you?
좋아요, 린지. 그쪽은요?
Fantastic, fantastic.
아주 좋아요, 최고예요.
What are we getting into in All Ears English today, Michelle?
미셸, 오늘 All Ears English에서는 어떤 주제를 다뤄볼까요?
Well Lindsay, I have a question.
음, 린지, 저 질문이 하나 있어요.
What would you say is one of the top experiences you've had in the past year?
지난 한 해 동안 했던 최고의 경험 하나를 꼽으라면 뭘 말하시겠어요?
Oh my gosh, it's hard to say.
어머, 고르기 어렵네요.
But probably hiking in Slovenia was amazing.
그래도 아마 슬로베니아에서 했던 하이킹이 정말 멋졌어요.
That altitude and just being in a new place was awesome.
그 고도, 그리고 새로운 곳에 있다는 것 자체가 최고였어요.
It's usually a travel experience for me.
저한테는 보통 여행이 그런 경험이에요.
What about you, Michelle?
미셸은요?
Oh yeah, for me, I guess it was a whirlwind of a year.
아 저는요, 정신없이 휘몰아친 한 해였던 것 같아요.
So I would just say moving in general.
그래서 그냥 '이사'를 통틀어서 말하고 싶어요.
Okay, I don't know if it was like the top experience, as if you would be traveling.
음, 여행처럼 '최고의 경험'이라고 할 수 있을지는 모르겠어요.
But it was pretty awesome to move into a house and just kind of start building a new life.
그래도 집으로 이사해서 새로운 삶을 시작하는 건 꽤 멋진 일이었어요.
So I would say that.
그래서 그걸 꼽을래요.
Yes, I love that, I love that.
네, 정말 좋네요, 너무 좋아요.
So, experience — you asked me about my top experience of the year.
자, '경험(experience)' — 올해 최고의 경험을 저한테 물어보셨죠.
Is that what we're talking about today on the show?
그게 오늘 방송에서 다룰 주제인가요?
We are, we are.
맞아요, 맞아요.
We're actually doing a miniseries — this is the first part.
사실 미니시리즈를 하고 있는데, 이게 그 1편이에요.
And guys, stay tuned, because the second part is going to be about a different way to use the word experience.
여러분, 기대해 주세요. 2편에서는 'experience'라는 단어를 다른 방식으로 쓰는 법을 다룰 거예요.
And we're going to do this over on the Business English podcast.
그건 Business English 팟캐스트에서 진행할 거예요.
So don't think, if you're not looking to excel at work — if you're just listening for fun — that it won't help. It still will.
그러니 '난 직장에서 잘하려는 게 아닌데' 하고 그냥 재미로 듣는 분들도, 도움이 안 될 거라 생각하지 마세요. 그래도 도움이 돼요.
This is not just for business, but it's going to be really good for the Business English podcast.
비즈니스용만은 아니지만, Business English 팟캐스트에 정말 잘 맞을 거예요.
So go ahead on over to that one and hit follow, because that one is coming out very soon.
그러니 그 채널로 가서 팔로우를 눌러주세요. 곧 올라오거든요.
I love it, I love it.
좋아요, 좋아요.
Yeah, go ahead and hit follow, hit the follow button, guys, so you don't miss a single episode.
네, 팔로우 버튼 눌러주세요, 여러분. 한 회도 놓치지 않게요.
Either here on All Ears English or over on Business English.
여기 All Ears English든, Business English든요.
But Michelle, we do have some poll results to share today.
그런데 미셸, 오늘 공유할 설문 결과가 좀 있어요.
We do, we do.
있죠, 있어요.
All right, so this is from episode 2371, 'Is This Seat Taken?'
자, 이건 2371화 'Is This Seat Taken?(이 자리 임자 있나요?)' 편에서 나온 거예요.
And Lindsay, what was the poll question?
린지, 설문 질문이 뭐였죠?
Okay, the poll question was: is it acceptable to save seats in crowded places in your culture?
네, 질문은 '당신의 문화에서는 붐비는 곳에서 자리를 맡아두는 게 괜찮은가요?'였어요.
We had a whole interesting conversation around saving seats.
자리 맡아두기에 대해 아주 흥미로운 대화를 나눴었죠.
And we thought maybe it's kind of cultural, this idea of saving seats.
자리를 맡아두는 게 어쩌면 문화적인 걸 수도 있겠다고 생각했어요.
And especially saving more than one seat next to you, right?
특히 옆에 한 자리 넘게 맡아두는 거요, 그쵸?
Yes, that was fun.
네, 재밌었어요.
So, is it acceptable to save seats in crowded places in your culture?
그래서, 당신의 문화에서는 붐비는 곳에서 자리를 맡아두는 게 괜찮나요?
So Lindsay, what were the results?
린지, 결과가 어땠어요?
All right, so our listeners — the verdict is: yes, it is acceptable, for 68% of our listeners.
자, 청취자분들 결과는요 — 68%는 '괜찮다'였어요.
And no for 31% of people that are listening to the show.
그리고 청취자의 31%는 '안 된다'였고요.
Very interesting breakdown here, Michelle.
아주 흥미로운 분포네요, 미셸.
Yeah, I would definitely be curious to learn more about it.
네, 저도 더 알아보고 싶어지네요.
It's always those things that you don't think too much about, right?
늘 평소엔 별로 생각 안 하는 것들이잖아요, 그쵸?
We don't think about, oh, saving seats around the world.
'전 세계의 자리 맡아두기 문화' 같은 건 평소엔 생각 안 하죠.
But it's always when you travel — those are the things that you kind of pick up on, how things are different.
그런데 여행할 때면 늘 그런 걸 알아차리게 돼요. 뭐가 다른지요.
But you don't think about it ahead of time, right?
그래도 미리 생각해 두진 않잖아요, 그쵸?
It's true, absolutely.
맞아요, 정말로요.
Wow, there are so many differences around the world.
와, 세상엔 정말 다른 점이 많아요.
But I think the thing that brings us together is the desire for connection.
그래도 우리를 하나로 묶어주는 건 '연결되고 싶은 마음'인 것 같아요.
I mean, that's what we're coming together around here in the show.
그게 바로 이 방송에서 우리가 함께 모이는 이유잖아요.
So using the correct vocabulary words is one way to do that, right Michelle?
그러니 올바른 어휘를 쓰는 게 그 방법 중 하나예요, 그쵸 미셸?
Love it. Yeah, exactly.
좋아요. 네, 정확해요.
So, talking about experience — we're going to talk about some really useful ways to refer to an important situation, something you've done, something like that.
자, 'experience' 얘기를 해볼게요. 중요한 상황이나 당신이 해본 일 같은 걸 가리키는 정말 유용한 표현들을 다룰 거예요.
So this is, you know, when we talk about work experience, that's kind of a different way to use that word.
음, '경력(work experience)'을 말할 때의 그 단어는 좀 다른 쓰임이거든요.
So we're going to talk about a slightly special way to use it.
그래서 우리는 조금 특별한 쓰임을 다룰 거예요.
So okay Lindsay, what's the first one?
자 린지, 첫 번째는 뭐예요?
Okay, so the first one we're talking about today is 'a' or 'an experience.'
네, 오늘 첫 번째로 다룰 건 'a experience' 또는 'an experience'예요.
Right, so this could be anything — a way to describe something that you've done, again, like you said.
네, 이건 뭐든 될 수 있어요. 말씀하신 것처럼 당신이 해본 일을 묘사하는 방법이죠.
So throwing out some common ones, here we have: a wonderful experience, a terrible experience, a learning experience.
흔한 것들을 좀 던져볼게요. 'a wonderful experience(멋진 경험)', 'a terrible experience(끔찍한 경험)', 'a learning experience(배움이 된 경험)'.
What else, Michelle, might we say?
또 뭐가 있을까요, 미셸?
You could say an unforgettable experience, a unique experience, a special experience.
'an unforgettable experience(잊지 못할 경험)', 'a unique experience(독특한 경험)', 'a special experience(특별한 경험)'라고 할 수 있죠.
Sometimes somebody might even say a once-in-a-lifetime experience, right?
가끔은 'a once-in-a-lifetime experience(일생일대의 경험)'라고도 하죠, 그쵸?
It's a cliche, but it's a good one, I think.
좀 진부하지만, 좋은 표현인 것 같아요.
Right, exactly, exactly.
네, 맞아요, 맞아요.
So let's do some examples here.
그럼 예문을 좀 해볼게요.
So, well, this one is for me.
음, 이건 제 얘기예요.
"I had a wonderful experience living in London. I will never forget it."
"I had a wonderful experience living in London. I will never forget it." (런던에서 산 건 정말 멋진 경험이었어요. 절대 못 잊을 거예요.)
Oh, for sure.
아, 당연하죠.
Any kind of — like we said at the top of the show — any kind of a chance to live abroad or travel is usually a wonderful experience.
방송 초반에 말했듯이, 해외에서 살거나 여행할 기회는 보통 멋진 경험이에요.
Sometimes it can be hard, right? But wonderful.
가끔은 힘들 수도 있죠. 그래도 멋져요.
Yeah, or here's another example.
네, 아니면 다른 예문도 있어요.
"I just had the best experience I've ever had at a nail salon."
"I just had the best experience I've ever had at a nail salon." (네일 살롱에서 인생 최고의 경험을 했어요.)
Best experience you've ever had at a nail salon — you have to go there!
네일 살롱 인생 최고 경험이라니 — 거기 꼭 가봐야겠네요!
I actually went to get my nails done recently.
사실 저 얼마 전에 네일 받으러 갔어요.
Yeah, I never do, but I had a photo shoot and I was like, 'Oh, I have to do my nails, right?'
네, 평소엔 안 하는데, 화보 촬영이 있어서 '아, 네일 해야겠다' 싶었어요.
It was fun, it was like pampering.
재밌었어요, 호강하는 기분이었죠.
You put your nails in there and, you know, it was great.
손톱을 거기 넣고 있으면, 아시죠, 정말 좋았어요.
Did you get a color, or were you more of a neutral?
컬러로 했어요, 아니면 좀 무난한 색으로 했어요?
I just got the neutral — just the gel and the neutral.
그냥 무난한 색으로 했어요 — 젤에 뉴트럴 컬러로요.
Oh, gel — I know, so fancy. Yes, exactly.
오, 젤이요 — 그쵸, 고급지죠. 네, 맞아요.
All right, here we go.
자, 가볼게요.
"You have to look at this as a learning experience."
"You have to look at this as a learning experience." (이걸 배움의 기회로 봐야 해요.)
"You may not love every minute of it, but it will get you to the next level."
"You may not love every minute of it, but it will get you to the next level." (매 순간이 좋진 않겠지만, 다음 단계로 데려다줄 거예요.)
So yeah, I think we do throw around this idea of experience, and describing the experience, a lot.
네, 우리는 '경험'이라는 개념과 그걸 묘사하는 말을 꽤 자주 쓰는 것 같아요.
And it's part of kind of coming of age too, in American culture.
미국 문화에서는 성장 과정의 일부이기도 해요.
Going to college is a learning experience.
대학에 가는 건 하나의 배움의 경험이죠.
Separating from your parents when you're 18, 19 years old is an experience, right?
열여덟, 열아홉 살에 부모님에게서 독립하는 것도 하나의 '경험'이에요, 그쵸?
Yep, yep, exactly.
네, 네, 맞아요.
I mean, Lindsay — you were talking about Slovenia, but any other experiences you want to share?
린지, 슬로베니아 얘기를 했는데, 또 나누고 싶은 경험 있어요?
What would you say has been your most unforgettable experience while traveling?
여행하면서 가장 잊지 못할 경험은 뭐였어요?
I know that's probably a tough question.
아마 어려운 질문이겠죠.
Yeah, they're all pretty unforgettable.
네, 다들 꽤 잊지 못할 경험이에요.
I mean, living in Japan dramatically altered my life.
일본에서 살았던 건 제 인생을 완전히 바꿔놨어요.
I just had dinner with — did I mention this on the show? — someone I hadn't seen in 20 years.
얼마 전에 저녁을 같이 먹었는데 — 이거 방송에서 말했었나요? — 20년 만에 본 사람이랑요.
Someone I had lived — not lived with — in Japan, but we were very close, and we were trained together as a group.
일본에서 같이 산 건 아니지만, 아주 가까웠고 한 그룹으로 함께 훈련받았던 사람이에요.
And it changed me, you know?
그게 절 바꿔놨어요, 아시죠?
When you go do something like that when you're 24 years old, it changes how you envision the rest of your life.
스물네 살에 그런 걸 하면, 남은 인생을 어떻게 그릴지가 달라져요.
What kind of work you're going to do, and how your life is going to look.
어떤 일을 할지, 인생이 어떤 모습일지까지요.
Right, so that would be it for me.
네, 저한테는 그게 바로 그거예요.
Yeah, absolutely. All right, love it. Okay.
네, 정말요. 좋아요, 너무 좋네요. 자.
So another thing you can just say is — and this is, I love this — do you ever say 'it was an experience'?
또 이렇게도 말할 수 있어요 — 이거 제가 정말 좋아하는데 — 'it was an experience'라고 해본 적 있어요?
Yeah, and I love this because we could say an awful lot without saying very much, right?
네, 제가 이걸 좋아하는 이유는 별말 안 하면서도 엄청 많은 걸 말할 수 있어서예요, 그쵸?
It's emphatic.
강조하는 표현이에요.
It's generally used to say something was a little crazy, maybe a little chaotic.
보통 뭔가가 좀 정신없거나, 어쩌면 좀 난리였다는 걸 말할 때 써요.
Maybe there's a — yeah, we're hinting at something maybe not that great, right?
뭔가 — 네, 그렇게 좋지만은 않았다는 걸 넌지시 비추는 거죠, 그쵸?
Let's give an example, Michelle.
예를 들어볼게요, 미셸.
All right, little role play here.
좋아요, 간단한 역할극 해볼게요.
"Hey, I heard you took your kids on the plane — how was your flight with your kids?"
"Hey, 애들 데리고 비행기 탔다면서요 — 애들이랑 비행은 어땠어요?"
"Woo, it was an experience."
"Woo, it was an experience." (와… 한마디로 '경험'이었죠.)
So when you hear me say that, what do I possibly mean?
제가 그렇게 말하면, 무슨 뜻인 것 같아요?
I gather that you survived it, right? You came out of it, but it was not easy, right?
어쨌든 무사히 넘겼다는 거죠, 그쵸? 해내긴 했지만 쉽진 않았다는 거요.
That's the key, right? Right, exactly, exactly.
그게 핵심이에요, 그쵸? 네, 정확해요.
And maybe you don't want to go into all the details for me today.
그리고 오늘 저한테 자세한 얘기까진 하고 싶지 않을 수도 있고요.
But you're just — I get it, okay? All right, it was a little challenging, what she did.
그냥 — 무슨 말인지 알겠어요. 네, '좀 힘들었구나' 하고요.
Yeah, right, right, right.
네, 맞아요, 맞아요.
Something was a little wild.
뭔가 좀 정신없었다는 거죠.
It could — I mean, it could be positive, but it's mostly to say it was wild or chaotic.
긍정적일 수도 있지만, 대개는 정신없거나 난리였다는 뜻이에요.
I mean, have you had any experiences like that recently?
그나저나 최근에 그런 경험 있었어요?
Oh, wild and chaotic experiences like that, Michelle?
아, 그런 정신없고 난리였던 경험이요, 미셸?
No, not recently — things have been relatively smooth, I would say.
아니요, 최근엔 없었어요. 비교적 순탄했던 것 같아요.
But, although, when I came back from California a few weeks ago, I was carrying back some heavy items.
그래도 몇 주 전에 캘리포니아에서 돌아올 때, 무거운 짐을 좀 들고 왔거든요.
And I had to load up the suitcase and lift it from the ground to pull it up into the overhead bin.
캐리어를 채워서 바닥에서부터 들어 올려 머리 위 짐칸에 넣어야 했어요.
That was kind of unwieldy and crazy, so I had to use the leg muscles.
그게 좀 다루기 힘들고 정신없어서, 다리 힘을 써야 했어요.
Yeah, so you could say, 'Oh my gosh, that was an experience.'
네, 그래서 "Oh my gosh, that was an experience(세상에, 정말 한 경험 했네)"라고 할 수 있죠.
Yeah, for me it was going on the plane with both of my kids.
네, 저한테는 두 아이를 다 데리고 비행기 탄 거였어요.
That's a true, a true thing.
그건 정말, 진짜였어요.
I can't imagine. I've seen it on TV, but I just don't know how people do it.
상상도 안 가요. TV에서 본 적은 있지만, 사람들이 대체 어떻게 하는지 모르겠어요.
All right Michelle, we are back.
자 미셸, 다시 돌아왔어요.
So is there another way that we use this term experience?
'experience'를 쓰는 또 다른 방법이 있나요?
Yeah, so this is one that comes about quite frequently, I think.
네, 이건 꽤 자주 나오는 것 같아요.
Have you ever heard somebody say 'you're paying for the experience'?
누가 'you're paying for the experience'라고 하는 거 들어본 적 있어요?
Yes, you hear that. Yeah, yeah, totally.
네, 들어봤어요. 네, 완전히요.
Especially when we're paying too much for something, right?
특히 뭔가에 너무 많이 낼 때요, 그쵸?
Exactly, yep.
정확해요, 네.
So yeah, this is an interesting one.
네, 이거 흥미로운 표현이에요.
I'm pretty sure this episode was probably inspired by this expression, because I feel like it comes up a lot.
이번 에피소드는 아마 이 표현에서 영감을 받은 것 같아요. 정말 자주 나오거든요.
So this is used when you want to say something is maybe overpriced for the service provided.
이건 제공되는 서비스에 비해 값이 비싸다고 말하고 싶을 때 써요.
Or simply that the quality isn't wonderful, but there's something special or unique about it that makes it worth it.
아니면 품질이 훌륭하진 않지만, 그만한 값을 하게 만드는 특별하거나 독특한 무언가가 있을 때요.
So to me, I think of like a theme restaurant — do you remember, did you have something called the Rainforest Cafe?
저한테는 테마 레스토랑 같은 게 떠올라요 — 혹시 'Rainforest Cafe'라고 있었던 거 기억나요?
Yeah, it sounds familiar, sounds familiar.
네, 익숙하네요, 들어본 것 같아요.
Yeah, growing up, you know, we loved to go to the Rainforest Cafe.
네, 어릴 때 우리는 Rainforest Cafe에 가는 걸 정말 좋아했어요.
And I actually don't know how much it was, because I was a kid, but I'm assuming it was expensive.
어렸을 때라 얼마였는지는 모르지만, 비쌌을 거라고 짐작해요.
And it's a really cool atmosphere.
분위기가 정말 멋지거든요.
It's not that there's anything special about the food, but you would say, 'Oh, you're paying for the experience.'
음식이 특별한 건 아니지만, "Oh, you're paying for the experience(아, 경험값을 내는 거지)"라고 하게 되죠.
Another one I can think of is — do you ever go to the Stardust Diner in New York?
또 떠오르는 건 — 뉴욕의 Stardust Diner 가본 적 있어요?
It sounds very familiar.
굉장히 익숙하게 들리네요.
I mean, that one — or what comes to mind for me is Benihana.
그것도 그렇고 — 저는 Benihana가 떠올라요.
Ah, that's the ultimate, right? Because you're paying to watch people flip things in the air.
아, 그게 최고죠. 사람들이 음식을 공중에 던지는 걸 보려고 돈을 내는 거니까요.
And you bring kids and they love it — there's onions flying and there's fire going, and a hibachi.
애들을 데려가면 정말 좋아해요 — 양파가 날아다니고 불이 솟고, 데판(히바치)도 있고요.
Yep, and the food's maybe not outstanding.
네, 음식이 그렇게 뛰어나진 않을 수도 있어요.
You could get better Japanese food somewhere else, but you're paying for the experience, right?
더 맛있는 일식은 다른 데서도 먹을 수 있지만, 경험값을 내는 거죠, 그쵸?
Yes, exactly.
네, 맞아요.
Or let me think — there was one I wanted to share.
잠깐 생각 좀 — 나누고 싶은 게 하나 있었는데.
Wait, what's another — wait, wait, wait, oh my gosh, I'll come back to it.
잠깐, 또 뭐였더라 — 잠깐만요, 어휴, 이따 다시 올게요.
But so let's do a little role play, okay? Here we go.
그럼 간단한 역할극 해볼게요, 네? 시작합니다.
"So how was the food?"
"So how was the food?" (음식은 어땠어요?)
"Uh, the food was okay, but really that's not what it's about — you're paying for the experience."
"음, 음식은 괜찮았어요. 근데 사실 그게 중요한 게 아니에요 — 경험값을 내는 거죠."
Of course, of course — acrobats at your seat, that's so much fun.
그럼요, 그럼요 — 자리에서 곡예를 보여주니, 정말 재밌죠.
And sometimes it's okay — yeah, we have to decide when we want to pay for the experience.
가끔은 괜찮아요 — 네, 언제 경험값을 낼지는 우리가 정해야 해요.
Maybe that's the event of the weekend, right? And that's what we're paying for.
그게 주말의 이벤트일 수도 있죠. 그걸 위해 돈을 내는 거예요.
But sometimes you're thinking, okay, I just want good food.
하지만 가끔은 '그냥 맛있는 음식이 먹고 싶어' 싶을 때도 있죠.
So I'm going to go more low-key and unknown, right?
그럴 땐 좀 더 소박하고 안 알려진 데로 가는 거예요, 그쵸?
Right, so — actually, now I know what I was going to say.
맞아요 — 아, 이제 무슨 말 하려던 건지 생각났어요.
I was going to go back to the Stardust Diner.
Stardust Diner 얘기로 돌아가려던 거였어요.
So the Stardust Diner is a restaurant in New York, and it's very popular.
Stardust Diner는 뉴욕에 있는 식당인데, 아주 인기가 많아요.
And it's kind of aspiring actors and actresses who sing at your seat.
배우 지망생들이 자리에서 노래를 불러줘요.
Well, not at your seat, but they kind of go all around the restaurant — they take turns singing.
음, 자리 바로 앞은 아니고, 식당 곳곳을 돌아다니면서 돌아가며 노래해요.
And they are incredible — I mean, they are just incredible, incredible singers.
정말 대단해요 — 진짜, 엄청나게 잘하는 가수들이에요.
But I wouldn't, like — and the food is diner food, and it's expensive diner food.
근데 저라면 — 음식은 그냥 분식 같은 거고, 그것도 비싼 분식이에요.
It's expensive food, I mean.
그러니까 비싼 음식이에요.
Like, I took my son there and we got like a bagel and a tuna melt.
아들을 데려가서 베이글이랑 참치 멜트를 먹었거든요.
I mean, this was probably a year ago, and it's just overpriced — the food is overpriced.
한 일 년 전쯤이었는데, 그냥 값이 너무 비싸요 — 음식값이 과해요.
But what you would say in that case is, 'It's okay, you're paying for the experience.'
그럴 때 하는 말이 "It's okay, you're paying for the experience(괜찮아, 경험값을 내는 거니까)"예요.
It's that there's something special that kind of warrants the extra money that you spend.
추가로 내는 돈이 아깝지 않게 만드는 특별한 무언가가 있다는 거죠.
Yes. Or we also say 'paying for the convenience,' but that's another episode for another day, right?
네. 아니면 'paying for the convenience(편의값을 내다)'라고도 하는데, 그건 다음 기회에 다룰 주제예요, 그쵸?
Another episode for another day. Oh, that's a good one. Yes, yes.
다음에 다룰 주제죠. 오, 그거 좋네요. 네, 네.
A bodega or something — totally different thing.
보데가(동네 편의점) 같은 거요 — 완전히 다른 얘기죠.
Yeah, for sure, totally different thing.
네, 그럼요, 완전히 다른 얘기예요.
But have you had any experiences recently where you felt you were paying for the experience?
그런데 최근에 '경험값을 내고 있구나' 싶었던 적 있어요?
Well, like I said, Benihana — we went there.
음, 말했듯이 Benihana요 — 거기 갔었어요.
I went with my extended family on Christmas Eve, or around the holidays.
크리스마스이브쯤, 연휴에 친척들이랑 같이 갔어요.
And I was like, 'Are we really going here?'
'우리 진짜 여기 가는 거야?' 싶었죠.
I didn't pay, though, so you know — my family treats, so I'm cool with it. That's fine.
근데 제가 돈을 낸 게 아니라서요 — 가족이 사주는 거라 저는 괜찮았어요. 그럼 됐죠.
So all right, that is a really fun one — I like that expression.
자, 이거 정말 재밌는 표현이에요 — 저 이 표현 좋아해요.
So Lindsay, let's do a role play here.
자 린지, 여기서 역할극 하나 해볼게요.
In this role play, you just went to a new spa, and I am asking you about it.
이 역할극에서는, 당신이 새로 생긴 스파에 다녀왔고 제가 그것에 대해 물어보는 거예요.
Oh yes, okay, here we go.
아 네, 좋아요, 시작할게요.
"All right, so how was it?"
"All right, so how was it?" (자, 어땠어요?)
"It was an experience."
"It was an experience." (한 경험이었죠.)
"Really? Yeah, I mean, it was good."
"정말요? 네, 뭐, 좋긴 했어요."
"There were tons of people there, super crowded. I don't know, maybe I'll go somewhere else next time."
"사람이 엄청 많았어요, 진짜 붐볐죠. 모르겠어요, 다음엔 다른 데 갈까 봐요."
"Oh well, you could try my place — it's pretty expensive, but you're paying for the experience."
"아 그럼 제가 가는 데 가보세요 — 좀 비싸긴 한데, 경험값을 내는 거예요."
"They have the most beautiful rooms and play the best music, and the staff is so nice — I'd say it's worth it."
"방이 제일 예쁘고 음악도 제일 좋고, 직원들도 정말 친절해요 — 그만한 값을 한다고 봐요."
"Okay, maybe I'll call them. I want to get the best experience possible."
"좋아요, 전화해 볼까 봐요. 가능한 최고의 경험을 하고 싶거든요."
"Definitely, you deserve it."
"당연하죠, 그럴 자격 있어요."
Nice, nice. Yeah, it makes me think of — have you ever heard of a beer spa?
좋아요, 좋아요. 이거 보니까 생각나는데 — '맥주 스파'라고 들어본 적 있어요?
This is so — no? — so bad.
이거 진짜 — 없어요? — 너무 웃겨요.
So there is a beer spa in Denver, and I've been to it a couple times.
덴버에 맥주 스파가 있는데, 저 몇 번 가봤어요.
Where literally they put beer and hops in the water, and it's supposed to have anti-inflammatory properties.
말 그대로 물에 맥주랑 홉을 넣는데, 항염 효과가 있다고 해요.
I'm not sure if I believe that.
그게 사실인지는 잘 모르겠어요.
And then you can drink beer in the spa — it's a whole thing.
그리고 스파 안에서 맥주를 마실 수도 있어요 — 아주 제대로예요.
So that is an experience, Michelle, right?
그러니 그건 하나의 'experience'죠, 미셸, 그쵸?
That's definitely probably paying for the experience.
그것도 분명 경험값을 내는 거예요.
It's like there's something so unique or special about it that you bake that into the price of the actual quality of something.
너무 독특하거나 특별한 무언가가 있어서, 그걸 실제 품질의 가격에 녹여 넣는 거죠.
It's so crazy, it's so crazy.
진짜 신기해요, 너무 신기해요.
So that's the kind of thing, you know — a once-in-a-lifetime experience.
그러니 그런 게 바로, 아시죠 — 일생일대의 경험 같은 거예요.
I probably wouldn't go back there regularly — I tried it once, it didn't knock my socks off.
저라면 거길 자주 가진 않을 것 같아요 — 한 번 가봤는데, 그렇게 감탄스럽진 않았어요.
You know — bonus phrase for today: 'knock my socks off.'
그래서 — 오늘의 보너스 표현이에요: 'knock my socks off(깜짝 놀라게 하다, 감탄시키다)'.
Knock socks off — yeah, I'm gonna put that one in there. That's a great one.
'knock socks off' — 네, 이것도 넣을게요. 정말 좋은 표현이에요.
Well, let's go through the role play, Michelle. So what did I say?
자, 역할극을 되짚어 볼게요, 미셸. 제가 뭐라고 했죠?
Mhm, okay, so I said, 'So how was it?' And you said, 'It was an experience.'
음, 네, 제가 "So how was it?"라고 했고, 당신은 "It was an experience"라고 했죠.
And when somebody says that, you know there's more to the story.
누가 그렇게 말하면, 뒷얘기가 더 있다는 걸 알 수 있어요.
Um, yes — there's a lot packed in there, there's a lot implied by saying that.
네 — 그 안에 많은 게 담겨 있어요. 그 말 한마디에 많은 게 함축돼 있죠.
And you have to use your intonation there, you know.
그리고 거기서 억양을 잘 살려야 해요.
"It was…" — and then you did a pause — "…an experience."
"It was…" — 그리고 잠깐 멈췄다가 — "…an experience." 이렇게요.
Yeah, 'it was an experience' — you definitely, and we can feel that there's a lot there, a lot of thoughts that I have, right?
네, 'it was an experience' — 확실히, 거기에 많은 게, 제 안에 많은 생각이 있다는 게 느껴지죠, 그쵸?
I have a lot of thoughts here.
저 여기 생각이 정말 많아요.
And then you said it's pretty — explaining my spa — um, it's pretty expensive.
그다음 당신은 — 제 스파를 설명하면서 — "꽤 비싸요"라고 했죠.
And what you mean by that is the spa near your home, in your neighborhood, the one you go to regularly, right Michelle?
그 말은 집 근처, 동네에 있는, 평소 다니는 그 스파를 말하는 거예요, 그쵸 미셸?
Right, right.
맞아요, 맞아요.
And I said, 'But you're paying for the experience,' and then I went on to say why.
그리고 저는 "But you're paying for the experience"라고 한 다음, 그 이유를 이어서 말했죠.
So I guess what I'm saying is there's nothing out of the ordinary about the actual massages or whatever you get.
그러니까 제 말은, 실제 마사지나 받는 서비스 자체는 특별할 게 없다는 거예요.
But it's so nice, maybe it's pristine, right? Everything is great, so it's worth it.
그래도 너무 좋고, 어쩌면 흠잡을 데 없이 깔끔하죠. 다 훌륭하니까 그만한 값을 해요.
I love it.
너무 좋아요.
And then I said, 'Okay, maybe I'll call them. I want to get the best experience possible.'
그리고 저는 "좋아요, 전화해 볼까 봐요. 최고의 경험을 하고 싶어요"라고 했죠.
So I'm just saying I want the best — I want to go to the best place I can find, right?
그러니까 제 말은 — 네, 최고를 원한다는 거예요. 제가 찾을 수 있는 최고의 장소에 가고 싶다는 거죠, 그쵸?
Exactly, yeah.
정확해요, 네.
I mean, this is an interesting episode, because you would think experience is such a common word — it's everywhere.
이거 흥미로운 에피소드예요. 'experience'는 정말 흔한 단어라고 생각하잖아요 — 어디에나 있죠.
But we do use it in very specific chunks to mark the moments of our lives, right?
그런데 우리는 인생의 순간들을 표시하려고 아주 특정한 덩어리 표현으로 써요, 그쵸?
This is talking about the moments of our lives.
이건 우리 인생의 순간들에 관한 거예요.
Think about what we've talked about today, Michelle — our travel experiences, times with our families at restaurants, relaxation.
오늘 우리가 얘기한 걸 생각해 보세요, 미셸 — 여행 경험, 가족과 식당에서 보낸 시간, 휴식이요.
This is what is going to come up in conversation for our listeners.
이게 바로 청취자분들의 대화에서 나올 것들이에요.
Yeah, exactly, this is really fun.
네, 맞아요, 정말 재밌어요.
So guys, head on over, make sure that you hit the follow button.
자 여러분, 가셔서 팔로우 버튼 꼭 눌러주세요.
Well, if you don't follow All Ears English yet, make sure you do that first of all.
아직 All Ears English를 팔로우 안 했다면, 우선 그것부터 해주세요.
But also head on over to Business English and hit follow, because you'll be getting part two of this series over there soon.
그리고 Business English로도 가서 팔로우를 눌러주세요. 이 시리즈의 2편이 곧 거기 올라올 거예요.
All right, sounds great, Michelle.
좋아요, 아주 좋네요, 미셸.
Well, I'll talk to you very soon. Take care.
그럼 곧 또 얘기해요. 잘 지내요.
All right, bye Lindsay. Bye.
네, 안녕 린지. 안녕히.